And welcome to part four of day two of week eight.
8주 차 둘째 날의 4부에 잘 오셨어요
Uh, there's a lot happening this week, and I have to tell you that this is the heftiest of the parts
이번 주에 할 일이 많은데 오늘 들어온 부품 중에 이게 제일
for today.
무거워요
Uh, let's get right into it.
Get it, get it, get it 바로 시작하죠
You remember, what we're going to do today is we're going to build some other kinds of prices and put
기억하세요 오늘 우리가 할 것은 다른 종류의 가격을 만들어
them all together to improve the accuracy of our ability to estimate the value of products.
함께 합치는 겁니다 제품의 가치를 정확하게 추정하기 위해서요 Put
And again, the reason we're doing this is an opportunity to revise on the various techniques we've
이 수업을 하는 이유는 우리가 배운 다양한 기술을 복습하고
learned about and solidify some of the learning, um, as well as being a fun exercise.
학습 능력을 강화하고 즐거운 운동이 될 수 있도록 하기 위해서죠
Uh, we're going to be using this random forest type of machine learning that we experimented with in
임의의 숲 학습 형태의 머신 러닝을 사용할 거예요 6주 차에 실험했던
week six.
거죠
That is a traditional ML, but we're going to be doing it differently.
전통적인 ML이지만 다르게 할 거예요
We're going to be using the vector embeddings that we have in chroma that are based on the, uh, hugging
크로마에 있는 벡터 내장 기법을 사용할 거예요 얼굴 문장을 끌어안는 변압기
face sentence transformer Vectorizer, which means that we're using Transformers and, uh, traditional
벡터라이저에 기반한 건데 트랜스포머와 머신 러닝을 함께 쓴다는 뜻이죠
So we'll start by doing some imports and set some constants.
몇 가지 수입과 상수 설정으로 시작하죠
This time I do remember to set the product vector, store constant, load the environment, load in
이번엔 제품 벡터를 설정하고 일관되게 저장하고 환경을 로드하고 테스트 데이터를 로드하는
the test data.
걸 기억하죠
We don't need the training data because it's sitting in Cromer and connect to Cromer itself, to the
훈련 데이터가 필요 없죠 그건 Cromer에 있고 Cromer 자체와 Cromer의
products collection in Cromer that we put in the variable collection and then we load in from Cromer.
제품 컬렉션에 연결되어 변수 컬렉션에 넣고 Cromer에서 로드하니까요
The results, which then gives us our vectors, our documents and our prices.
결과로 벡터와 문서, 가격을 알 수 있죠
So with that we are now going to look at random forests again.
이제 임의의 숲을 다시 살펴볼게요
And you may remember this line which was how we did it last time.
이 대사 기억하실지 모르겠네요 지난번엔 이렇게 했죠
We train a random forest regressor.
무작위로 숲으로 퇴행하는 사람을 훈련해요
Uh, this here njobs is how many concurrent processes can run.
여기 이 놉은 동시 진행 가능한 절차의 수예요
And if you put minus one, it will use up your entire machine.
Get 1을 누르면 컴퓨터 전체를 다 쓰게 돼요
It will run a process for every core.
모든 코어에 대한 프로세스를 실행하죠
And it really hammers my box.
제 상자를 부수죠
And my M1 Mac takes about an hour to run this and I ran it already, so you should, uh, time it,
제 M1 Mac은 실행하는 데 1시간 정도 걸립니다 이미 실행했으니 여러분은 박스에
uh, to to fit your box and only use -one inch here.
맞게 시간을 재고 1인치만 사용하세요
If you can afford to step away and let your machine hum for a little bit.
잠시 물러나서 비트를 감상할 수 있다면요
Once that's done, you can then save the model weights to a file using this useful utility Joblib dot
그게 끝나면 모델 무게를 파일에 저장할 수 있습니다 유용한 유틸리티 Joblib.Doplib를 이용해서요
dump, which is from again scikit learn.
scikit learn에 있는 거죠
And you can then provide a model and then just save it, save those model weights.
그럼 모델을 제공해 저장할 수 있죠 모델 웨이트를 저장해요
And what I then do is load it back in again so that I don't have to run the hours worth of training.
그런 다음 다시 로드합니다 훈련 시간을 낭비하지 않으려고요
Now, what I do here is I load in three agent objects the specialist agent, the frontier agent, and
이제 세 가지 요소를 장착합니다 전문 요원, 개척지 요원 그리고 임의
the random forest agent.
숲 요원이죠
Let's take a quick look in the agents folder and look at those.
에이전트 폴더를 잠깐 살펴보고 그걸 살펴보죠
The specialist agent is one that we already looked at before.
특수 요원은 이미 봤던 거예요
We already wrote this.
이미 써놨잖아요
This is Productionized code.
이건 프로덕션화된 코드예요
Uh, that is uh, basically in the init in the in the constructor for the specialized agent, we use
기본적으로 이닛이라는 건데 컨스트럭터라는 특수 에이전트예요 모달이라고
the we call modal.
하죠
By saying modal class lookup.
ModalCass-out을 사용해서요
And we provide our service name and class name and we instantiate that class.
서비스 이름과 클래스 이름을 제공하고 클래스를 인스턴스화하죠
And then when we're actually calling this to price, we simply say self dot price dot price, which
그리고 가격으로 호출할 때는 셀프.Price.Price라고 입력합니다
is the function, the modal function dot remote.
함수죠 함수 . remote이요
And that you'll remember is how we tell modal.
그 방법만 기억하면 돼요
We don't want to run this locally.
이걸 로컬로 실행하면 안 돼요
We want to call out to the cloud, run it remotely and bring back the results, and then it returns
클라우드에 호출해 원격으로 실행하고 결과를 가져오면 결과를 반환하죠
it.
전에 봤던 특수 요원이에요
If we look at the frontier agent you'll see what's here is the code that we went through last time as
프런티어 에이전트를 보면 여기 있는 코드는 지난 시간에 살펴본
I said polished up, made to look nice with comments with the parameters are identified.
것으로 매개 변수를 식별하고 주석을 달아 멋지게 만들었죠
There's docstring.
의사봉합이 있어요
There's the docstrings here.
여기 도서가 있어요
There's type hinting to describe what kinds of objects we're working with.
우리가 작업하는 개체를 설명하는 형식 힌트가 있어요
And this is the kind of process that you would go through to take code from being Jupyter Notebook code
이런 과정을 거쳐야만 코드를 얻을 수 있어요 주피터 노트북 코드에서
to being ready for production.
생산 준비 단계로요
And typically you wouldn't write this in JupyterLab, you would be doing this in an IDE like VSCode
보통 JupyterLab에서는 작성하지 않아요 IDE에서 하죠 VSCode나
or PyCharm is my favorite.
PyCam 같은 거요
And you would build it there because it will do things like help you with the type hints and fill in
여기에 구축하면 힌트 형식이나 검프 일부를 채우는 데 도움이
some of this gumpf.
될 거예요
But you can you can use JupyterLab if you wish.
원한다면 주피터랩을 이용해도 돼요
Um, so this is the frontier agent.
이쪽은 프런티어 요원이에요
And now if I look at the random forest agent, this is super simple.
이제 임의의 산림청소를 보면 아주 간단해요
In the constructor, we first of all create our the sentence transformer, the model that we use to
생성자에서 먼저 문장 변압기를 만듭니다 벡터를 만들기 위해 사용하는
create a vector.
모델이죠
And then we load in the model that we just saved a second ago.
그런 다음 조금 전에 저장한 모델을 로드하죠
Uh, and then when it comes to the actual doing and inference running a price, uh, what we do is we
실제 작업과 가격 실행 추론에 관해선 우리가 하는 일은 먼저 제품
first take the description that's passed in the description of our product, we encode it into a vector.
설명에 통과된 설명을 취합니다 벡터로 암호화하죠
And then we call self dot model.predict with that vector.
셀프.Model이라고 하고요 벡터로 예측하세요
And that gives us our random forest results and we return it.
그러면 임의의 숲 결과를 받고 반환하죠
It's as simple as that.
아주 간단해요
You'll see I do a max of zero here.
0으로 최대치를 설정했어요
I suggest that I floor it at zero so it can't return negative numbers.
음수를 반환하지 못하게 0에서 밟는 게 좋겠어요
I don't know if if it would or not.
그럴지는 잘 모르겠어요
I think I might have seen it in an earlier version, and so that seemed like a sensible precaution to
초기 버전에서 본 것 같아요 그래서 그게 현명한 예방책 같았죠
take.
적자를 예상하면 안 되니까요
Okay.
네
So anyways that is the those are the the agents.
어쨌든 저건 에이전트란 거죠
We can then instantiate those agents.
그 에이전트를 인스턴스화할 수 있죠
Now this function here description is exactly the same as we did in the last one.
여기 이 함수는 설명입니다 지난 번과 정확히 같죠
We simply take the item and we take its prompt and we pull out the to the nearest dollar.
그냥 항목을 가져다가 가장 가까운 달러로 끌어내는 거죠
The the introductory text the header.
도입부 문자가 헤더에 들어가요
And we also pull away the prices dollars.
달러도 떼어낼 거예요
So we just get back to the blurb itself, the simple description of the product.
다시 광고 문구로 돌아가죠 제품에 대한 간단한 설명이요 Get up
Um, and with that in mind, we can now have a function, uh, RF, which is randomforest, which will
그걸 염두에 두고 RF라는 함수를 쓸 수 있어요 랜덤포레스트라는 함수인데 항목을 설명으로
take an item, turn it into a description, call our Randomforest agent price to price.
바꾸는 거죠 랜덤포레스트 에이전트 가격을 랜덤포레스트로 불러요
It.
그것요
Uh, and with that in mind, You, of course, remember our great test harness tester test.
그걸 명심하고 하니스 테스트 기억하시죠?
We can now test this with 250 data points and see how the random forest performs.
이제 250개의 데이터 포인트로 시험할 수 있습니다 무작위 숲이 어떻게 작동하는지 보죠
Here we go.
시작할게요
There's quite a lot of red in there.
붉은색이 꽤 많네요
You remember last time?
지난번 일 기억나요?
It got about 97, I think.
97 정도였던 것 같아요
Uh, let's see how it does.
어떻게 되나 보죠
Uh, and it's, in fact, just a hair worse than it was last time.
사실 지난번보다 아주 조금 더 나빠졌어요
But obviously this is super close.
하지만 이건 정말 가깝네요
It's basically the same.
기본적으로 똑같아요
So the random forest, given, uh, these improved vectors versus the word two vec vectors, gives essentially
무작위 숲은 개선된 벡터와 두 베카 벡터가 같은 수를 제공하죠
And you can see visually it's doing okay.
겉으로 보기에는 괜찮아요
There's a sort of a wrong slope here.
비탈이 좀 안 좋아요
And uh, some problem uh, um, over there.
그리고 문제가 좀 있어요 저기예요
But generally speaking, it's done.
하지만 일반적으로 보면 다 끝난 거예요
Laudably.
칭찬할 만해요
Well, uh, not like our recent models though.
요즘 모델과는 다르지만요
So that is the random forest.
저기가 무작위 숲이에요
And in the next video, we are going to move to the ensemble model that brings everything together.
다음 비디오에선 모든 걸 하나로 묶어주는 앙상블 모델로 넘어갈 거예요
I will see you there.
거기서 봐요